Hoffman Family Papers
© 2006 University of Connecticut
- Series V: Newspaper and Periodical Clippings, undated, 1936-1997
  - News, 1988 January, [1. n/a, n/a, unknown, advertisement of Kurt Vonnegut's "A Letter to the Next Generation"; 2. n/a, n/a, unknown, cartoon about racism; 3. Graham Allison and Katie Smith, "A Democracy With Ever Fewer Voters?," New York Times, editorial about political participation in the United States; 4. n/a, n/a, New Patriot, articles on Pat Robertson and politics in Chicago; 5. David S. Broder, "They've both seen heights and depths, but at opposite times," unknown, reflections on the lives of Vice President Bush and former Secretary of the Navy James Connally; 6. Robert Wagman, "Dole campaign is in disarray," unknown, problems within Dole's campaign team during the 1988 presidental run; 7. Merle Black and Earl Black, "Don't Underestimate Bush," unknown, Democrats should consider Bush a threat to victory, not a pushover; 8. n/a, n/a, unknown, list of presidental hopefuls and their ages; 9. Katherine Seelye, "Leader of state GOP for Bush," unknown, Pennsylvannia state leader asked to join Bush campaign; 10. William A. Henry, III, "The Spartan," unknown, reflections on the Dukakis campaign; 11. n/a, n/a, n/a, press release from the NBAU National Office Staff; 12. Patrick J. Buchanan, "Just as the Cold War was being won, the Democrats turned chicken again," unknown, editorial on American foreign policy; 13. Richard Reeves, "Bush is sounding like a Democrat," unknown, news analysis on Bush's move to the center; 14. Katherine Seelye, "McCarthy to announce his 3d presidential run," unknown, Eugene McCarthy to run for president; 15. S.A. Paolantonio, "Jackson backed by Usry," unknown, Republican mayor of Atlanta backs Jesse Jackson's presidential run; 16. n/a, n/a, unknown, Dukakis to on CSPAN debate; 17. unknown, unknown, New Orleans Times, report on Gore's campaign and Super Tuesday; 18. n/a, "Drug testing upheld," unknown, short piece on a court ruling upholding the NCAA's drug testing policy; 19. unknown, "Playboby and Pit Bulls," unknown, Hoffman and Jonathan Silvers' article on Iran hostage scandal is ignored by mainstream media; 20. n/a, n/a, n/a, oil price chart from 1970-1988; 21. n/a, n/a, n/a, United Press International abstracts from 1988; 22. n/a, n/a, n/a, article clips concerning wealth in America; 23. unknown, unknown, unknown, Weinberger claims he is innocent of all corruption charges; 24. n/a, n/a, n/a, press release from National Emergency Civil Liberties Committee on library surveillance; 25. unknown, "Group, in rally, decries Bush at his office," unknown, anti-CIA demonstration in front of Bush's office; 26. n/a, n/a, n/a, random quotes; 27. unknown, "Don't drop your zipper for the gipper," unknown, reflections on Hoffman's life; 28. Chicago 68 + 20, 1988; 29. unknown, "Where '88 front runners will stay," unknown, hotel accomdations for the presidental hopefuls; 30. David S. Broder, "Democrats should point finger at themselves," unknown, Democratic Party has interal issues that account for his poor showing in the polls; 31. Andrew Kopkind, "Jesse's Movement," The Nation, Jackson's unsuccessful campaign for the presidentsy and its effect on the Democratic Party; 32. Richard Benedetto, "Dems' state of confusion," USA Today, analysis of the presidential race; 33. Carl M. Cannon, "Hart's new issues old hat to 6 rivals," unknown, analysis of the Hart campaign; 34. Susan Bennett, "Dukakis eases his stance on Guard," unknown, analysis of the Democratic hopefuls; 35. Michael Oreskes, "Bush and Dukakis Try to Capitalize on Latest Debate," New York Times, new analysis of the Bush and Dukakis campaigns; 36. Joe DeChick, "Most mothers want a job, too," USA Today, study shows that most mothers would like to remain in the work force; 37. unknown, "Hoffman on Dem VP: Glenn Gets Yippie's Yippee; Bentsen Gets a Yuk," unknown, Hoffman comments on the potentional candidates for the Vice President on the Democratic ticket; 38. Jerry W. Byrd, "Montco worker, asked to go, says link to Jackson is issue," unknown, worker is fired for being a Jackson delegate; 39. n/a, n/a, unknown, cartoon about the Iran/Contra scandal; 40. Richard Benedetto, "Candidates keep up pace on final lap," USA Today, analysis of the election; 41. unknown, "Dole Targeted With TV Spots on Apartheid Record," Fenton Communications," Dole challenged on his South Africa record; 42. n/a, n/a, unknown, advertisement for Ronald Reagan Countdown Calender; 43. Andrew Kopkind, "Is Jesse the Great White Hope?," The Nation, news analysis of Jackson's campaign; 44. Lance Morrow, "1968," Time, reflections on 1968; 45. Marc Cooper, "Newspeak," L.A. Weekly, news analysis of mainstream media; 46. n/a, n/a, New York Times, letter to the editor about Iowa caucuses; 47. unknown, "Memo to Haig," The Nation, Haig's role in the Iran/Contra scandal; 48. Frank Lynn, "Ethics Unit Investigating Elections Board," New York Times, review of potentiall illegal contributions in Poughkeepsie race; 49. Larry Eichel, "Democratic rivals assail Gephardt," The Philadelphia Inquirer, Gephardt targeted in last round of presidential debates; 50. n/a, n/a, New York Times, editorial "What Is George Bush Hiding?," concerns Iran/Contra scandal; 51. Gerald M. Boyd, "Iran Deal Haunting The Bush Campaign," The Nation, the reoccuring questions surrounding the scandal have put Bush on the spot; 52. n/a, n/a, The Nation, cover stories "It Seems to Work" and "Oh. What a Screwy System" on the Iowa caucus; 53. Woody Allen, "Am I Reading the Papers Correctly?," New York Times, editoral in protest of Israeli policy; 54. Katherine Seeyle, "Legislator to head Simon campaign in Pa.," The Philadelphia Inquirer, the actions of the respective presidential campaigns in Pennsylvannia; 55. Michael A. Lipton, "Campaign '88 and TV: America Speaks Out," TV Guide, findings of a TV poll on the campaigns; 56. n/a, n/a, The Philadelphia Inquirer, Sunday January 24th 1988 news section.] (Box 8:196)
  - News, 1988 February, [1. Michael Albert, "Jackson vs. Technocracy," Z Magazine, reflections on the progressive character of Jackson's campaign; 2. n/a, n/a, New York Times, three articles on the campaigns: "Hart Tries to Disperse Cloud on Campaign," "Robertson May Be Cause for Uncertainty in Iowa," and "Dukakis Aide's Out for 'Stunt';" 3. Martha Honey and Tony Avirgan, "The C.I.A.'s War," The Nation, C.I.A. activities in Puerto Rico; 4. Arlene Stein, "Agnos Did It the Grass-Roots Way," The Nation, reflections on Agnos' successful campaign for mayor of San Francisco; 5. Frank Donner and James Ledbetter, "Deregulation By Sleaze," The Nation, corruption and deregulation during the Reagan years; 6. Jean Becker, "Grouchy voters knock system," USA Today, most voters desire different candidates for the election; 7. Larry Eichel, "Next 9 days will defeine the nature of the race," The Philadelphia Inquirer, news analysis of the Iowa caucus; 8. Richard Lacayo, "Bad Habits Die Hard," The Nation, FBI is accused of political snooping and racial harassment; 9. Associated Press, "Bush, Dole downplay feud on eve of Iowa vote," The Star-Ledger, Democratic and Republican candidates push for support; 10. Bernard Weinrub, "The Anger in Bob Dole Is One Key to His Power," New York Times, analysis of the Dole campaign; 11. Walter Shapiro, "Getting to Know Them," The Nation, political and personal analysis of the presidental hopefuls; 12. Lawerence Zuckerman, "Bushwhacked!," Time, report on Rather's controversial interview of Bush; 13. n/a, n/a, New York Times, editorial "Who Was Unfair on the Air?" concerning the Rather-Bush debate; 14. Joseph J. McDermott, "Area lawmakers give response to primary," unknown, views of local officials on the primary results; 15. Richard Benedetto, "Winnowing-out' starts today," USA Today, analysis of the impact of the Iowa caucus; 16. Robert S. Boyd and Larry Eichel, "Gephardt, Dole leading in Iowa poll," The Philadelphia Inquirer, updates on the Iowa caucus; 17.n/a, n/a, Extra!, articles on media, "Murdoch and the Corporate Media Clan" and "Social Security, the Candidates and the Media;" 18. unknown, "America's political future," Daily Intelligencer/Montgomery County Record, profile of candidate Pierre du Pont, IV; 19. Associated Press, "Dole wins, Gephardt leads," The Star Ledger, results of the Iowa caucus; 20. Associated Press, "Robertson's surprising advance on Bush went unreported in the polls," The Star-Ledger, incorrect prediction in the Iowa caucus; 21. R.W. Apple, Jr., "Stunning Result Carries a Grim Message for Bush," New York Times, news analysis of the Iowa caucus; 22. E.J. Dionne, Jr., "Dole Wins in Iowa With Robertson 2d," New York Times, report on the outcome of the Iowa caucuses; 23. Associated Press, n/a, unknown, two articles - "Politicians defend state against 'Iowa-bashing'" about the problems lodged against the caucuses and "Bush disappointed, 'not down' after loss" Bush reflects on loss; 24. David Moberg, "Simon's soft liberalism leads to soft support," In These Times, analysis of Paul Simon campaign; 25. Martin A. Lee, "Congressional oversight and Iran-contra myopia," In These Times, review of "Out Of Control" on the Iran-contra scandal; 26. John B. Judis, "Behind the masks: Tricky Dick and Simple Simon," In These Times, analysis of the Gephardt and Simon campaign; 27. n/a, n/a, In These Times, editorial on "The meaning of DSA's endorsement of Jackson: and "Fighting LaRouche in the very worst way"; 28. Andrew Rosenthal, "New Hampshire Ponders Robertson," New York Times, analysis of the New Hamsphire caucus; 29. unknown, "With Little Tiem to Exult or Weep, Candidates Get Set for the Next Round," New York Times, profiles of the candidates; 30. unknown, unknown, New York Times, polls on the caucuses; 31. Jack Germond and Jules Witcover, "Bush has to show more to voters than his credentials," reflections on the New Hampshire caucus; 32. Larry Eichel, "Iowa recast the Republican contest, but changed little for Democrats," Philadephia Journal-Inquirer, new analysis of New Hampshire caucuses; 33. Owen Ullman, "After Iowa loss, a change for Bush," Philadelphia Inquirer, analysis of the Bush campaign; 34. unknown, "Dole tries to forge link with Robertson," New York Post, Dole campaign courts Robertson; 35. Anne Braden, "Jackson campaign: Ideal vehicle for movement," Guardian, campaign worker explains her faith in the Jackson campaign; 36. Kevin J. Kelley, "Jackson campaign mya turn corner in Vermont," Guardian, analysis of the Jackson campaign; 37. Susan Bennett and Bill Arthur, "Gephardt now underdog to Dukakis," The Philadelphia Inquirer; analysis of the Democratic candidates; 38. Susan Levine, "A lot new in N.H. this time," Philadelphia Inquirer, political orientation of the New Hampshire electorate; 39. Michael Greskes, "Bush Does an About-Face After Iowa," New York Times, change in Bush's strategy; 40. Susan Bennett and Larry Eichel, "Bush points to ties to President," the Philadelphia Inquirer, analysis of the Republican campaign; 41. unknown, "(illegible) the political stereotypes of N.H.," Philadelphia Inquirer, changes in the political orientation of New Hampshire; 42. Robert S. Boyd and Andrew Cassel, "Gephardt, Simon in race for 2d," Philadelphia Inquirer; analysis of the Democratic caucus; 43. John B. Judis, "Gephardt Grasped The No. 1 Issue," New York Times, analysis of the Gephardt campaign; 44. unknown, "Bush waves off some queries from reporters," The Philadelphia Inquirer, Tension between Bush and the media; 45. Sara Diamond, "Pat on the Head," The Nation, review of a biography of Pat Robertson; 46. Richard Pollak, "And Then There Was One," The Nation, review of The Media Monopoly by Ben Bagdikian; 47. (illegible) Ullmann, "Bush takes a bolder stance after Iowa," The Philadelphia Inquirer, changes in the Bush campaign strategy; 48. Robert S. Boyd and Larry Eichel, "N.H. battle is a quest for survival," The Philadelphia Inquirer, analysis of the potential fall-out after the primaries; 49. Ann Grimes, "Agenda Gap," Village Voice, analysis of the Democratic candidates; 50. Joe Conason and James Ridgeway, "The 'Miracle' Worker," Village Voice, analysis of the Dukakis campaign; 51. Jeff Nason and Malcolm Byrne, "Will the real George Bush please fess up?," In These Times, Bush's role in the Iran-contra scandal; 52. David Moberg, "Babbitt makes pitch for workplace democracy," In These Times, analysis of Babbitt's agenda for the economy; 53. Elizabeth Hess, "Art of the State," Village Voice, CIA bases and areas of operation in the United States; 54. Laura McClure, "On the line with Jesse," Guardian, interview and analysis of the Jackson campaign; 55. Associated Press, "Bush, Dukakis exult in wins; Babbitt, du Pont near exits," Daily Intelligencer, results from the New Hampshire primaries; 56. David Corn, "Unmasking the Other Bob Dole," The Nation, expose on Dole's voting record; 57. Thomas Ferguson, "Dick and Trade," The Nation, analysis of Gephardt's trade policy proposals; 58. David Moberg, "Democrat's foggy road out of Iowa," In These Times, analysis of the Democratic candidates; 59. Marc Shaffer, "Jackson takes lead on gay issues," Guardian, Jackson's stance on gay rights issues; 60. Susan Bennett, "Robertson defends self on hostages," Philadelphia Inquirer, tensions in the Robertson and Reagan relationship; 61. John H. Makin, "Candidates Err About Both Deficits," New York Times, critique of campaign platforms; 62. Michael M. Weinstein, "What the candidates say about welfare," unknown, issue analysis; 63. unknown, "Dukakis, Bush win in Maine, Republicans spar in Atlanta," Daily Intelligencer, report on primary results; 64. Robin Toner, "Dukakis and Bush Triumph in Maine," New York Times, report on primary results; 65. Richard Cohen, "Pay heed to Gephardt's message," Philadelphia Inquirer, analysis of the Gephardt campaign; 66. National Student News Service Vol. 2 No. 10 February 27th 1988; 67. n/a, n/a, The Nation, campaign analysis pp. 32-46 February 29th 1988; 68. n/a, n/a, n/a, collection of original copies of news articles that already appear.] (Box 8:197)
  - News, 1988 March, [1. Jimmy Breslin, "Jackson's delegates are solid," unknown, article in support of the Jackson campaign; 2. David S. Broder, "Super Tuesday is achieving what Southerners wanted to prevent," unknown, impact of Super Tuesday on the diversity of Southern politics; 3. Associated Press, "Babbitt, du Pont quit race; Bush stands behind tough commercials," unknown, analysis of the campaigns prior to Super Tuesday; 4. n/a, n/a, USA Today, Supreme Court reviews the legality of drug testing for rail workers; 5. Doreen Carvajal and Carl M. Cannon, "Jackson's strong finishes show a broadened appeal," unknown, Jackson campaign is gaining momentum; 6. n/a, n/a, Guardian, Elections section with articles on Jesse Jackson and Michael Dukakis; 7. Associated Press, "Bush leading Dole in Vermont primary," Daily Intelligencer/Montgomery County Record, analysis of the Vermont primary; 8. S. A. Paolantonio, "Behind the scenes of a Bush rally, with TV as king," Philadelphia Inquirer, analysis of the Bush campaign's emphasis on their media image; 9. Susan Bennett, "Dukakis criticized by Bush," Philadelphia Inquirer, report on the campaigns, with emphasis on Bush and Robertson; 10. Lee Bandy, "Robertson, Bush push hard in S.C.," Philadelphia Inquirer, report on the South Carolina Republican primary; 11. n/a, "The Devil Did It," The Nation, editorial on the Robertson campaign 12. Randall Rothenberg, "In Search of George Bush," The New York Times Magazine, analysis of Bush and his campaign; 13. Hank Pearson, "Use upgrades to attain a touch of class," USA Today, airplane travel tips; 14. n/a, "Thinking About the '60s," Village Voice, special report on the cultural, political, and social climate of the 1960s; 15. Ann Davis, "Robertson may be born again in South," In These Times, analysis of the Robertson campaign; 16. Thulani Davis and James Ridgeway, "Southern Man," The Nation, report on the Jackson campaign; 17. Richard Benedetto, "Today is SUPER shakeout," USA Today, television coverage of the Super Tuesday results; 18. Associated Press, "Candidates scramble for votes," unknown, report on efforts to mobilize voters for Super Tuesday; 19. Dick Russell, "Groups push candidates for action on toxic issues," In These Times, candidate stances on toxic and chemical waste; 20. n/a, n/a, In These Times, Dialogue section on In These Times stance on the Democratic Socialists Association support for the Jackson campaign; 21. Michael Harrington, "Socialists help shape the best in our politics," In These Times, editorial from the head of DSA on the role of American socialists; 22. John B. Judis, "Gephardt's neo-populism appeals to blue-collar vote," In These Times, analysis of the Gephardt campaign; 23. n/a, n/a, Guardian, Jackson Campaign section; 24. Richard Reeves, "Super Tuesday has turned out to be a super flop," Philadelphia Inquirer, reflections on Super Tuesday results; 25. William A. Ryan, "President Jackson?," Guardian, editorial in support of the Jackson campaign; 26. n/a, "Bush Dominates GOP Voting; Dukakis, Gore, Jackson in Split," Philadelphia Inquirer, two separate articles on the Republican and Democratic primaries; 27. Ginger Varney, "The Super Pig-Out!," L.A. Weekly, reflections on Super Tuesday; 28. Leslie Phillips, "POLL: Bush tops Democrat pack," USA Today, report on USA Today poll on the presidental race; 29. Hal Spencer, "Jackson Edges Out Dukakis in Alaska," New York Times, Jackson wins the Alaska primary; 30. n/a, "Who's Living Up to the Arias Plan?," New York Times, editorial on peace plans in Central America; 31. Bernard Weinraub, "High Aides Urging Dole to Quit Race; He Cancels TV ads," New York Times, debate within the Dole campaign over whether he should quit the race; 32. James R. Carroll, "Hart quits; says voters have spoken," Philadelphia Inquirer, Gary Hart ends campaign for the second time; 33. George F. Will, "Celebrate now, Bush, for the numbers say you won't in fall," prospects for Dukakis look strong; 34. R. W. Apple, Jr., "Glory Days," New York Times, analysis of the presidental hopefuls; 35. Michael Oreskes, "Jackson's Success Earns the Trust Of Many Who Once Feared Him," New York Times, Jackson campaign gaining mainstream respectibility; 36. Associated Press, "Gary Hart quits race," Sunday Intelligencer/Montgomery County Record, Hart exits race and Dole attempts to overcome Bush; 37. Isbael Wilkerson, "On Primary Day in Chicago, Lowly Race Is a Main Event," New York Times, report on the Chicago races; 38. Larry Eichel and Angelia Herrin, "Dole says he'll stay in the race," Philadelphia Inquirer, Dole to stay in race in spite of poor election results; 39. Robert S. Boyd, "Today's Illinois primary a major test for candidates," Philadelphia Inquirer, analysis of the Illinois primary and the potential ramifications; 40. Evans Witt, "Dole, Simon fight for lives," Bucks County Courier Times, report on the Republican candidates; 41. Mike Royko, "Picking a candidate: The sneaky approach," Bucks County Courier Times, satirical editorial about the positions of the leading Republican and Democratic candidates; 42. Associated Press, "Dole presses on; Jackson is even," unknown, analysis of the remaining candidates; 43. John B. Judis, "The GOP's slow road to destruction," In These Times, analysis of the decline of local Republican organizations; 44. Andrew Galameau, "Pat Robertson's support is broad and bared," In These Times, report on the Robertson supporteres; 45. Maureen Santini, "Dukakis and Dole seeking miracles," Daily News, analysis on the upcoming primaries; 46. Richard Benedetto and Jessica Lee, "Illinois vote: 'It's not over' is rallying cry," USA Today, faltering campaigns stake their futures on the Illinois primary; 47. Doreen Carvajal, "Jackson near Dukakis in delegates," Philadelphia Inquirer, report on the Democratic hopefuls; 48. Jean Becker, "Bush on roll; Dems on wild ride," USA Today, USA Today poll on presidental hopefuls; 49. Associated Press, "Simon defeats Jackson in Illinois," Daily Intelligencer/Montgomery County Record, report on the primary results; 50. Associated Press, "Paul Simon's victory revives 'broker' talk," Daily Intelligencer/Montgomery County Record, concerns about a deadlocked Democratic convention; 51. n/a, n/a, USA Today, Election Line sidebar with short pieces on the race for delegates; 52. Susan Page, "Unconventional Campaign Wisdom," Newsday, editorial on the direction of the campaigns; 53. Joseph B. Treaster, "U.S. Troops Arrive at Honduras Base to Show Support," New York Times, US troops in Honduras after Nicaragua n troops enter country in pursuit of contras; 54. n/a, "The Power Broker," Newsweek, special report on the Jackson campaign; 55. unknown, "Bush wins Puerto Rico primary," Daily Intelligencer/Montgomery County Record, report on recent primary victories; 56. n/a, "The Big Mo," Time, special report on the campaigns and the frontrunners going into the national conventions; 57. Michael Kinsley, "It's time to give Michael Dukakis his moment in the sun," Daily Intelligencer/Montgomery County Record, editorial in support of Dukakis campaign; 58. Chris Conway, "Ken endorses Bush for GOP nomination," Philadelphia Inquirer, New Jersey governor endorses Bush; 59. Associated Press, "Gov. Kean endorses Bush; Gore, Gephardt campaign," Daily Intelligencer/Montgomery County Record, New Jersey governor endorses Bush and Gore and Gephardt campaigns continue in spite of waning support; 60. James Reston, "the '88 Race at Halftime," New York Times, editorial that analyzes the current state of the respective campaigns; 61. n/a, "Jackson is transforming American politics," In These Times, Jackson's campaign infuses left politics into the mainstream; 62. John J. Judis, "Super Tuesday reshuffles the Democratic deck," In These Times, analysis of the Super Tuesday results; 63. Jack Colhoun, "McFarlane pleads guilty; North et al indicted," Guardian, Iran-contra scandal; 64. Gus Saunder, "Patching up cabbage's sudden smelly reputation," The Boston Herald, cabbage recipies; 65. Larry Eichel, "Money may not win primaries, but it certainly helps," Philadelphia Inquirer, impact of donations on campaigns; 66. Chris Conway, "Kean urges Bush to state own views," Philadelphia Inquirer, Kean tells Bush to state own views even if they conflict with Reagan; 67. Akinshiju C. Ola, "Jackson campaign gathers new head of steam," In These Times, strong showing in Massachusetts; 68. n/a, n/a, USA Today, Election Line pieces; 69. Kenneth B. Noble, "Bills to Raise Minimum Wage Advance in a Ready Congress," New York Times, political debate over raising the minimum wage; 70. Eleanor J. Bader, "Feminists Wish for Woman Candidate," Guardian, Jackson is encouraged by NOW and NARAL to select a woman vice president; 71. Associated Press, "Jackson concerns Democrats," Daily Intelligencer/Montgomery County Record, movement in the Democratic Party to ensure that Jackson does not receive the nomination; 72. Leslie Phillips, "3 factors have aided Jackson," USA Today, key factors behind Jackson's surge in popularity.] (Box 8:198)
  - News, 1988 March, [1. n/a, n/a, n/a, folder #1 of assorted original news articles; 2. n/a, n/a, n/a, folder #2 of assorted original news articles.] (Box 8:199)